Kimberly Love

Washington, D.C. | 513-939-6511| kimberlymlove15@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u> | Blog: <u>Medium</u> | <u>Portfolio Website</u>

FULL-STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

I am a dedicated and innovative software engineer with experience in frontend, backend, and full stack development. My diverse background in physical therapy and youth athletics brings a unique perspective that enriches my approach to crafting innovative technical solutions. My commitment to continuous education drives my effort to stay knowledgeable about new technologies, positioning me as an asset.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, Flask, SQL, SQLite, Flask-SQLAlchemy, JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, OOP, ORM, RESTful APIs, Git, GitHub

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

GoodSport - Github | Demo

A sports team schedule management app that allows users/players to be added to a team and view all events associated with their team, while coaches can add, update and delete events for their teams.

- Implemented CRUD functionality, enabling account creation, event management, and efficient data manipulation
- Established key relationships among Teams, Coaches, Players, and Events through designing a relational database structure with Flask-SQLAlchemy and SQLite
- Incorporated secure password hashing using bcrypt, enhancing data protection by encrypting user passwords
- Enforced data validation rules for player and user information during creation and updates, ensuring data integrity
- Integrated RESTFUL API routes with Flask and Python for streamlined frontend-backend communication
- Developed an auto-login route if user doesn't deliberately logout using the Session object in Python
- Incorporated client-side routing with React Router to emulate a Multi-Page Application (MPA) experience within a Single-Page Application (SPA)

FitConnect - Github | Demo | Live Site (Deployed on Render, can take 1-2 minutes to spin up)

FitConnect seamlessly blends fitness logging with a social media twist, where users can share workout insights, post reflections on stored routines, and create new shareable workouts for others to engage with and provide feedback on.

- Integrated form validations for Login and Signup forms, utilizing React state management for real-time UI error messages based on user input
- Developed backend user-centric Posts functionality, enabling creation, editing, and deletion of workout-related posts
- Implemented an efficient filter feature in the Posts section, enhancing content exploration for users

FlatStop - Github | Demo

A virtual game store that offers an immersive shopping experience where users can explore, curate and buy/sell their favorite games, all through simple commands.

- Developed a Python-based Command Line Interface (CLI) application, creating an immersive virtual game store
- Enhanced interactivity by incorporating a dynamic bargaining feature for game sales
- Added a login and account creation feature, ensuring a more secure and personalized experience
- Leveraged Python's SQL capabilities to seamlessly map Python classes to a SQLite database to perform CRUD
- Introduced a shopping cart feature, allowing users to conveniently acquire multiple games in a single-transaction
- Implemented fine-tuned search functionality as a way to filter games based on criteria such as game rating and title

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

OrthoVirginia, Physical Therapy Technician - McLean, VA

April 2018 - July 2023

- Managed a 6-person team of technicians and oversaw scheduling, training and daily office operations for the techs
- Assisted the Physical Therapists during patient treatment by providing joint distractions and guided joint mobilizations
- Worked hands-on with patients through therapeutic exercises

DC Soccer Club, Travel Coach - Washington, DC

August 2017 - June 2023

- Coached and trained multiple teams of ages 5-14, while also overseeing all team and administrative operations
- Developed and implemented practice plans that are both instructive and stimulating to promote player development
- Evaluated and assessed player performance to provide individualized reports for player growth and development

Source Physical Therapy and Wellness, Physical Therapy Technician - Arlington, VA December 2016 - April 2018

• Aided Physical Therapists during individualized patient treatment sessions, therapeutic exercises and documentation

EDUCATION

Flatiron School July 2023 - November 2023

Full Stack Web Development | Backend: Python and Flask | Frontend: JavaScript and React

Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN

August 2012 - May 2016

• Bachelor of Science | Major: Human and Health Sciences